All right, welcome back guys.
This is part eight to the Ads RX Advanced Editor training.
Thank you for making it this far. You've gone through a lot of stuff,
and now we're actually going to begin the editing process.
But before we do that,
I wanted to give you guys an overview of what this process actually looks
like, so you know what to expect. And throughout the training,
we'll go into detail of how to do each and every step,
but knowing what's gonna come next is gonna help you guys visualize what's to
come. So let's just jump straight into it.
This is the 11 stages of editing and launching creative. Okay,
so based off of, um, you know, our agency and the work that we do for clients,
these are the 11 steps that we do, you know,
as a post-production slash creative strategist.
And I just wanna go through this one by one, so we're all on the same page here.
And, um, so at this point, you've come to, uh,
organizing your files, organizing your B-roll, organizing your shots, you know,
having that toolbox of assets pre, uh,
basically pre-organized preassembled so that you can begin the actual editing
process. Okay? So number one, before getting started into your video, I highly,
highly, highly recommend modular modularizing your clips. Uh,
we spoke about this in the last module and showing you and the,
the next training, I'm gonna show you exactly how to modularize your clips.
This is gonna be so valuable for you, uh,
not just for your upcoming edit, but for future edits.
And so anything that you haven't modularized yet, I highly, highly, highly,
highly recommend doing that first. Okay?
This is going to save you a ton of time later on. So when you do that,
you're basically going to scrub your footage and extract just the best clips,
and then you're going to name them according to the shot.
So if it's a pain point, if it's a demonstration, if it's a feature,
if it's whatever, and then you're going to re-export that as, uh,
as its own MP four, which then you can upload to your, um,
your, your Google Drive or your air or wherever you're putting it,
so that now you can go backwards and have that asset available at any
time to pull into your videos so that you can just kind of extract what's,
what's needed, put it into your timeline, and boom, you, there you go.
It saves you a ton of time having to go back and forth, uh, looking for,
for good footage. Number two. Okay,
so next we're gonna assemble the timeline as well as the music.
This is where we do, we throw down our shots,
whether we have a script or we don't have a script. Um, you know,
our timeline is basically where we start to organize everything.
So if you've done the modularizing ahead of time,
this is going to allow you to speed up that assembly process. Uh, so, uh,
but regardless, if you have it, you can still begin to cut on your timeline.
But here we're really just trying to figure out what the flow of this video is
going to be. Once we've decided this is of logical flow,
this fall follows the ADA format,
then we're going to start adding the bells and whistles as I'd like to call it.
Uh, adding titles, overlays and effects. Okay?
This is when we start to spice up our video. Uh, we start to add titles.
We start to add bullet points or TikTok formats. We start to add overlays,
and this is where the ads arex, uh, overlays come very,
very handy. Uh, these are things we don't have to recreate from scratch.
We can just throw it onto our video and it makes it that much better looking.
And then lastly, we start adding effects. So we use, uh,
film impact for all of our transitions. I I really love their work.
They're amazing. It's super fast, it's super efficient. So we'll have a link,
uh, to film impact down below. And then as another shortcut, we use another, um,
preset. Uh, it's like a, it's like an artificial scale in and scale out,
which I love. Um, it, it, it saves me time in the key framing side,
so we'll definitely link that as well. So next is color correction.
Uh, it says here, fix any glaring color issues, but don't go overboard,
especially if it's just U G C. Honestly, with the U G C stuff,
less color correction is better, from my opinion. Uh, you know,
it doesn't require too much, and the more raw that it looks, the better.
But if you're working with lifestyle, if you're working with more commercial,
uh, footage and overall ad style,
then you're gonna definitely want to color correct it and, um, you know,
be very precise with that. Next is when you start adding subtitles.
Uh, I highly,
highly recommend using the auto transcribe feature to
basically, if you have any dialogue for it to run through,
then you have all of your captions already. Uh,
and then you can stylize your captions however way you want,
and I'll show you a little trick on how to convert that into an actual, um,
an actual graphic layer so that you can add transitions between it. Uh,
next will be your audio levels. All right,
so this is where you set limiters and boosters.
Boost up as much as you can the audio without it peaking,
but then also set a cap so that it doesn't go overboard. You're not peaking,
you're not hitting red.
So those are some just little pointers there once you have that timeline in
place. Okay, next we're going to set up our hook variations.
And that's that first three, three seconds of the video.
This is where you start stacking all of your hooks in the, that,
that window of time. And I'll show you exactly how to do that.
And once you do that, then we want to export our first hook. Okay?
So export your first hook variation to be reviewed before finalizing
all of your hooks. This is so, so important. If you're working on a team,
if you have clients,
if anybody else is looking at your video besides you, um,
you need to be, uh, getting approval before.
Because what's gonna happen is if you don't get approval,
and let's say you export 10 or 20 different videos and there's a typo,
or you know, there's a glitch or you did something wrong,
you're gonna have to go backwards and re-edit everything or re-export
everything. And that is just a pain in the ass. So whatever, you know,
wherever you're working, whatever you're doing,
make sure you have that approval first. And make sure whoever you're talking to,
Hey, are we good on this before I export?
'cause that's gonna save you a ton of time and a ton of headache. All right?
That's just from personal experience. So number nine, optional, get, uh,
your review opinion. You know, this could be anybody, honestly. Like,
if you don't have anybody, ask your wife, ask, ask your husband, um, ask,
ask a friend. You know, just they're gonna notice things that you didn't notice.
Um, and it's always good to get a little bit of feedback because when you are so
invested in the video, sometimes you can't see things or notice things.
So you kind of have that macro looking back approach and you're able to kind
of be, okay, uh, I,
I see where you're getting at because they're seeing it for the first time,
right? So definitely recommend doing that.
So once you've gotten their green light,
next you gotta export all of your remaining hooks,
and this is when you start cranking out your variations.
And then following a very, uh, I would say strict naming convention,
it's very important. 'cause if you don't follow a naming convention,
you're gonna get really lost and you're not gonna know what is what,
and then it's gonna get really just gets really hairy,
especially if you're pumping out 20, 50 variations. You gotta know what's what.
So I'll show you how to do that. And then lastly,
if you guys have a tracking system in place, um, we use Airtable, or you know,
some people use Google Sheets or Google Docs,
that's where you want to start updating all of your information.
Once the video is uploaded in Google Drive or in Air,
you can also update the tracking system that we have,
and I'll show you what we use. Um,
and maybe you can get some inspiration or even use that same, uh,
tracking system, so to speak. So on the next module, uh,
it's a separate module on how to actually modularize your footage.
So it's very important that you walk through that and then you do it for
yourself before you move on to the next stage. Okay?
This is gonna save you a ton of time in the, in, in the future. So, um,
watch that video after this,
and then we'll get into assembling our video and getting that
down and dirty. All right guys, thanks for watching this,
and I'll see you the next one.